One of the main assumptions of multiple linear regression models,
多重线性回归模型的主要假设之一
is that our predictor variables are uncorrelated with one another.
是我们的预测变量彼此不相关
We want our predictor variables to be correlated with our response,
我们希望预测变量与反应变量相关
but not with one another.
而不是彼此之间具有相关性
In this example where we're looking at the characteristics of homes,
在这个例子中 我们要观察房屋的特点
you can imagine that the size of the home,
你可以假设房屋大小
the number of bedrooms,
卧室数量
the number of bathrooms are all pretty related to one another.
卫生间数量都存在相关性
We might expect larger homes to have more bedrooms and more bathrooms.
我们可能认为房屋越大 拥有越多的卧室和卫生间
We can get a quick look at the relationships between
我们使用 seaborn 快速观察一下
each pair of variables in our dataset using seaborn.
每对变量之间的关系
Here you can see I read in seaborn as sb,
这里你可以看到我读取 seaborn 为 sb
and I'm using matplotlib inline so that will see the graphics.
我使用 matplotlib inline 这样可以看到图形
Seaborn has this really nice thing called a pairplot,
Seaborn 包含的 pairplot
which allows us to view the relationship between each of our variables.
可以让我们观察每个变量之间的关系
Here, I want to look at the relationships between each of these three x variables.
这里我想要观察这三个 x 变量之间的关系
So 'area, 'bedrooms' and 'bathrooms'.
即面积 卧室和卫生间
You can see that each of these relationships has
可以看到这些关系
pretty strong positive relationships between one another.
彼此之间具有极强的正相关
So, in this corner you can see the bathrooms
所以你可以发现卫生间和
versus the area has a pretty positive relationship,
面积具有很强的正相关
area versus the bedrooms,
面积和卧室之间
bedrooms versus the bathrooms,
卧室和卫生间之间也是如此
and let's see here.
我们看一下这里
I think that's all. Bathrooms vs the area,
我觉得这样可以了 卫生间和面积的关系
area vs. the bedrooms.
面积和卧室的关系
So, these three plots essentially match these three plots,
那么这三个散点图与这三个相匹配
just what on x and y axis changes.
随着 x 和 y 轴发生变化
Now let's try fitting a multiple linear regression model,
现在我们使用者三个系数
using these three coefficients.
试着拟合多重线性回归模型
First, we'll create our intercept as usual.
首先我们通常要创建截距
I run in statsmodels as sm,
我运行 statsmodels 简写为 sm
so I'm going to fit sm.OLS as- so the thing we want to predict is the
那么我将要这样拟合 sm.OLS 所以我们要预测的内容
'price' and what we're going to use
是“价格” 使用截距
is the 'intercept' as well as each of these x variables.
和所有这些 x 变量
I'm just going to copy them from here.
我从这里复制一下
And then, we store that in our linear model.
然后我们把它存储在线性模型中
We do it now.
现在完成了
So this is interesting,
有意思的是
even though we'd expect all area,
虽然我们希望面积
bedrooms and bathrooms to have the same relationship with the response,
卧室和卫生间与反应变量存在相同的关系
that is as they increase we'd expect the response to increase,
即随着它们增加 反应变量也应该增加
the bedrooms has a negative coefficient associated with it.
但卧室与反应变量存在负系数
So, even though price and bedrooms have a positive relationship between one another,
那么虽然价格和卧室与其他变量存在正相关
in our multiple linear regression model it showed up negative.
但是在多重线性回归模型中 两者呈现负相关
The interpretation of this coefficient is now counter-intuitive to
对这一系数的解释与我们直觉上认为的是相反的
the relationship we'd expect and what is actually true in the bivariate case.
在双变量例子中实际上为真
This is one potential side effect of having multicollinearity in our model,
这是模型中多重共线性的一个潜在副作用
is these flipped coefficients from what you expect to be true.
即这与你认为是正确的系数恰好相反
Another common way to identify our predictors is correlated with one another,
另一个常见的方式是认为我们的预测值之间具有相关性
besides the plot that we saw appear is with
除了我们看到的散点图
something called variance inflation factors, or VIFs.
还有方差膨胀因子 简写为 VIF
A link to a helpful post in this topic is provided below.
下面提供了对于这个话题进行有效说明的链接
From statsmodels, we can calculate the VIFs for each of our x variables like this.
从 statsmodels 中 我们计算得出每个 x 变量的方差膨胀因子
So here, this dmatrices is something that we read in a peer from patsy.
这里的矩阵是我们从 patsy 中读取的
This allows us to create our equation for x and y,
可以让我们创建 x 和 y 的方程式
and they'll give back matrices that we then
方程式可以得到矩阵
pass through this variance inflation factor function,
然后我们传递到方差膨胀因子函数中
which we read in from statsmodels.
方差膨胀因子可以写入 statsmodels
Within the price using intercept,
利用截距得到价格
and the area, and the bedrooms and the bathrooms.
以及面积 卧室和卫生间
So here, it looks like the intercept was provided for
这里我们已经得到了截距
us so I ran it again to get rid of the two intercepts,
所以我再次运行 消除两个截距
which is kind of strange.
看起来有点奇怪
We can see that the VIFs for each variable are
我们可以看到每个变量的方差膨胀因子
available through this VIF data frame that I created.
都可以从我创建的方差膨胀因子DataFrame中获取
We likely would want to remove at least one of these two variables
我们想要删除两个变量中的至少一个
here as both of their variants inflation factors are larger than 10.
因为两者方差膨胀因子都大于 10
There's a bit more discussion on this topic in the next video and then,
在接下来的视频中将继续讨论这一话题
you'll try this yourself.
然后你可以自己尝试一下